Finding Aid for Wisconsin Land & Lumber Company records, 1871-1920
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- William Mueller Company, 1899-1921
  - LaBranche
    - Ledger, April 1904-September 1905 (Volume 10)
    - Mill Book, 1905 (Volume 11)
    - Pay Roll, 1904-1906 (Volume 12)
    - Pay Roll, 1907-June 1911 (Volume 13)
  - Blaney
    - Accounts and Sales, 1909-1921 (Volume 14)
    - Journal, April 1908-April 1914 (Volume 15)
- Photographs
  - Album A (part; microfilm negative) (Box 47, Reel 53)
  - Photocopies of images
    (originals on indefinite loan to the IXL Museum; scans of images available on disk in box)
    - Logging scenes; logging camps (Box 49)
      (folder no. 1)
    - Railroads; railroad survey team (Box 49)
      (folder no. 2)
    - Milling operations (Box 49)
      (folder no. 3)
    - Factories (Box 49)
      (folder no. 4)
    - Views of company factories and mills 5 (Box 49)
      (folder no. 5)
    - Miscellaneous company operations (Box 49)
      (folder no. 6)
    - Company offices and stores (Box 49)
      (folder no. 7)
    - Hotels and boarding-houses (Box 49)
      (folder no. 8)
    - Hermansville schools, churches, and public buildings; local bicycle club; city views (Box 49)
      (folder no. 9)
    - Menominee River Boom Company's dam, 1900 (Box 49)
      (folder no. 10)
  - Digital photographs of images originally housed at the Bentley Library, now on indefinite loan to the IXL Museum, 70 images (Box 50)
    (computer disk 1; photocopies in box 49)
  - Digital photographs: Blaney aerial views, etc., 197 images (Box 50)
    (computer disk 2)
  - Digital photographs: Simmons and Blaney views, 1542 digital images (Box 50)
    (computer disk 3)
  - Digital photographs of albums A-Q with descriptive index to ca. 2000 images (.XLS and .PDF) (Box 50)
    (computer disk 4)
  - Photograph albums (A-P) received from the IXL Museum, 2007
    (also located in part on CD-ROM disks)
    - Early village of Hermansville -- Late 1800s and early 1900s (Box 50, Reel 1)
      (album # A)
    - Village of Hermansville and Blaney, 1917-1940s (Box 50, Reel 1)
      (album # B)
    - Village of Hermansville-, 1950s (Box 50, Reel 1)
      (album # C)
    - Lumber camps and Logging operations -- Blaney and Hermansville; late 1800s and early 1900s (Box 50, Reel 1)
      (album # D)
    - Misc. photos of Hermansville, 1912-1949 (Box 50, Reel 1)
      (album # E)
    - Village of Hermansville and industrial buildings, 1940s-1960s (Box 50, Reel 1)
      (album # F)
    - Examples of flooring (convention exhibits) (Box 50, Reel 1)
      (album # G)
    - Commercial establishments, outside view of buildings, residences & offices (Box 50, Reel 1)
      (album # H)
    - Numbered proofs where IXL flooring was installed (Box 50, Reel 1)
      (album # I)
    - Numbered cuts of IXL bull's eye, letterheads, office forms, maps, etc. (Box 50, Reel 1)
      (album # J)
    - Aerial photos of Hermansville taken by Abrams Aerial Survey Corp of Lansing (Box 50, Reel 1)
      (album # K)
    - Aerial photos continued (Box 50, Reel 1)
      (album # L)
    - Aerial photos continued (Box 50, Reel 1)
      (album # M)
    - G. Harold Earle Personal Albums (Box 50, Reel 1)
      (album # N)
    - G. Harold Earle Personal Albums (Box 50, Reel 1)
      (album # O)
    - G. Harold Earle Personal Albums (Box 50, Reel 1)
      (album # P)
- Records received from IXL Museum in, 2007
  (file descriptions provided by IXL Museum)
  - Daily reports by William Ellsworth (Box 50, Reel 2)
  - Letters from Julius Meyer (Box 50, Reel 2)
  - Daily reports from Mr. Benson to Mr. Meyer (Box 50, Reel 2)
  - Reports written by Mr. Newell Nightingale (Box 50, Reel 2)
  - Reports written by Mr. Alva Crofoot (Box 50, Reel 2)
  - Reports by W.P. Findheisen (Box 50, Reel 2)
  - Edwin P. Radford daily reports (Box 50, Reel 2)
  - Later Radford letters (Box 50, Reel 2)
  - Additional Radford letters, 1883-1886 (Box 50, Reel 2)
  - Correspondence containing Hermansville History (Box 50, Reel 2)
  - Charles Augustus Ebert -- Letters (Box 50, Reel 2)
  - History of Blaney Park-Picture Albums-Miscellaneous photos, aerial photos (Box 50, Reel 3)
  - History of Wisconsin Land & Lumber Co.-Jean Worth manuscript, 33 chapters (Box 50, Reel 3)
  - Chronological. History of Blaney Park-Simmons Lumber-Earle Lumber-Letters, 1906-1912 (Box 50, Reel 4)
  - Letters and miscellaneous papers, 1880-1899 (Box 50, Reel 4)
  - Old newspapers, manuals, personal letters; teaching certificates, Dr. Earle, etc., 1878-1944 (Box 50, Reel 4)
  - Correspondence 1870-1884 and supplies 1881-1889 (Box 50, Reel 4)
  - Orders, styles of letterheads, 1870-1880s (Box 50, Reel 4)
  - Letters; equipment for Hermansville, logs, applications (Box 50, Reel 4)
  - Correspondence Ebert wedding write-up, Dinkey Locomotive, 1880-1889 (Box 50, Reel 5)
  - CJL Meyer correspondence (Before Hermansville) Early, 1870s (Box 50, Reel 5)
  - Death Certificate H. Meyer, personal life CJL Meyer, etc. (Box 50, Reel 5)
  - IXL Co. Newsletters, April 1923-June 1928 (Box 50, Reel 5)
  - CJL Meyer Letters, 1871-1881 (Box 50, Reel 6)
  - Wisconsin Land & Lumber Co Letters, June 1884-December 1885 (Box 50, Reel 7)
  - Wisconsin Land & Lumber Co Letters (cont.) (Box 50, Reel 8)
  - Newspaper clippings re: Upper Peninsula (Box 50, Reel 8)
  - Newspapers from, 1972 (Box 50, Reel 8)
  - CJL Meyer Letters, 1885 (Box 50, Reel 9)
  - CJL Meyer Letters (cont.), 1885 (Box 50, Reel 10)
  - CJL Meyer Letters, 1887-1888 (Box 50, Reel 10)
  - CJL Meyer Letters (cont.), 1887-1888 (Box 50, Reel 11)
  - CJL Meyer Letters (cont.), 1887-1888 (Box 50, Reel 12)
  - CJL Meyer Letters, 1892-1908 (Box 50, Reel 12)
  - CJL Meyer Letters (cont.), 1892-1908 (Box 50, Reel 13)
  - CJL Meyer Personal Letters, 1894 (Box 50, Reel 13)
  - CJL Personal Letters (cont.), 1894 (Box 50, Reel 14)
  - CJL Meyer Personal Letters, 1894-1896 (Box 50, Reel 15)
  - CJL Meyer Personal Letters (cont.) (Box 50, Reel 16)
  - Wisconsin Land & Lumber Co. Letters, 1901-1908 (Box 50, Reel 16)
  - Wisconsin Land & Lumber Co. Letters (cont.), 1901-1908 (Box 50, Reel 17)
  - Letters and lands owned -- Accounts, 1882-1887 (Box 50, Reel 17)
  - Letter and lands owned (cont.) (Box 50, Reel 18)
  - E.P. Radford Diary, 1881-1885 (Box 50, Reel 18)
  - Wisconsin Land & Lumber Co. records, by-laws and minutes, 1883-1900 (Box 50, Reel 18)
  - Powers-Spalding Tribune, August 16, 1929-July 25, 1930 (Box 50, Reel 18)